In 1970, marijuana /ˌmærɪˈwɑːnə/ was classified as a
schedule 1 drug in the United States:
the strictest designation /ˌdezɪɡˈneɪʃən 指定/ possible,
meaning it was completely illegal and had
no recognized medical uses.
For decades, this view persisted
and set back research on the
drug's mechanisms /ˈmɛkəˌnɪzəm 机理/ and effects.
Today, marijuana/ˌmærɪˈwɑːnə/’s therapeutic /ˌθɛrəˈpjuːtɪk 有疗效的/ benefits
are widely acknowledged,
and some nations have legalized medical
use or are moving in that direction.
But a growing recognition for marijuana’s
medical value doesn’t answer the question:
is recreational marijuana use
bad for your brain?
Marijuana acts on the body’s
cannabinoid /kænəbinɔid 大麻素/ system,
which has receptors all over
the brain and body.
Molecules /ˈmɒlɪˌkjuːl 分子/ native to the body,
called endocannabinoids /内源性大麻素/,
also act on these receptors.
We don’t totally understand the
cannabinoid /kænəbinɔid 大麻素/ system,
but it has one feature that provides
a big clue to its function.
Most neurotransmitters /ˌnjʊərəʊtrænzˈmɪtə 神经传递介质/ travel from
one neuron /ˈnjʊərəʊn 神经元/ to the next
through a synapse /ˈsaɪnæps 神经键/ to propagate /ˈprɒpəˌɡeɪt  传播/ a message.
But endocannabinoids /内源性大麻素/ travel
in the opposite direction.
When a message passes from the
one neuron /ˈnjʊərəʊn 神经元/ to the next,
the receiving neuron releases
endocannabinoids.
Those endocannabinoids travel backward
to influence the sending neuron—
essentially giving it feedback from
the receiving neuron.
This leads scientists to believe that
the endocannabinoid system
serves primarily to modulate /mɔdjuleit 调节/
other kinds of signals—
amplifying /ˈæmplɪˌfaɪ 扩大；详述/ some and diminishing /dɪˈmɪnɪʃ 减小/ others.
Feedback from endocannabinoids slows
down rates of neural /ˈnjʊərəl 神经的/ signaling.
That doesn’t necessarily mean it slows
down behavior or perception /pəˈsɛpʃən 知觉；感觉/, though.
For example, slowing down a
signal that inhibits /ɪnˈhɪbɪt 禁止，抑制/ smell
could actually make smells more intense.
Marijuana contains two
main active compounds /ˈkɒmpaʊnd 混合的/,
tetrahydrocannabinol /,tetrə,haidrəkə'næbinɔl 四氢大麻酚/ or THC,
and cannabidiol /大麻二酚/, or CBD.
THC is thought to be primarily responsible
for marijuana’s psychoactive /ˌsaɪkəʊˈæktɪv  能作用于精神的/ effects
on behavior, cognition, and perception /pəˈsɛpʃən 洞察力 看法/,
while CBD is responsible for
the non-psychoactive effects.
Like endocannabinoids,
THC slows down signaling by binding /baɪnd 绑/
to cannabinoid receptors.
But it binds to receptors all over
this sprawling /sprɔːl  伸开手足躺/, diffuse /dɪˈfjuːz  扩散/ system at once,
whereas endocannabinoids are
released in a specific place
in response to a specific stimulus /ˈstɪmjʊləs 刺激/.
This widespread activity coupled with
the fact that the cannabinoid system
indirectly affects many other systems
means that each person’s particular
brain chemistry, genetics,
and previous life experience largely
determine how they experience the drug.
That’s true much more so with marijuana
than with other drugs
that produce their effects through one
or a few specific pathways.
So the harmful effects, if any, vary
considerably from person to person.
And while we don’t know how
exactly how marijuana
produces specific harmful effects,
there are clear risk factors that
can increase peoples’ likelihood
of experiencing them.
The clearest risk factor is age.
In people younger than 25, cannabinoid
receptors are more concentrated
in the white matter than
in people over 25.
The white matter is involved in
communication,
learning, memory, and emotions.
Frequent marijuana use can disrupt
the development of white matter tracts /trækt 道/,
and also affect the brain’s ability to
grow new connections.
This may damage long-term learning
ability and problem solving.
For now, it’s unclear how severe /sɪˈvɪə 严重的/ this
damage can be or whether it’s reversible.
And even among young people, the risk
is higher the younger someone is—
much higher for a 15 year old than a
22 year old, for instance.
Marijuana can also cause hallucinations /həˌluːsɪˈneɪʃən 幻觉/
or paranoid /ˈpærəˌnɔɪd 偏执狂患者；妄想症患者/ delusions /dɪˈluːʒən 欺骗/.
Known as marijuana-induced /ɪnˈdjuːsd 引起 感应的/  psychosis /saɪˈkəʊsɪs 精神病/,
these symptoms usually subside /səbˈsaɪd 减弱/
when a person stops using marijuana.
But in rare cases, psychosis
doesn’t subside,
instead unmasking a persistent /pəˈsɪstənt 持续的/
psychotic /saɪˈkɒtɪk 精神病患者/ disorder.
A family history of psychotic disorders
like schizophrenia /ˌskɪtsəʊˈfriːnɪə 精神分裂症/ is the clearest,
though not the only,
risk factor for this effect.
Marijuana-induced psychosis is also
more common among young adults,
though it’s worth noting that
psychotic /saɪˈkɒtɪk 精神病患者/ disorders
usually surface in this age range anyway.
What’s unclear in these cases
is whether the psychotic disorder
would have appeared without
marijuana use—
whether marijuana use triggers it early,
is a catalyst /ˈkætəlɪst 催化剂；诱因/ for a tipping point /转折点/ that
wouldn’t have been crossed otherwise,
or whether the reaction to
marijuana is merely an indication
of an underlying disorder.
In all likelihood /ˈlaɪklɪˌhʊd 可能，可能性/, marijuana’s role varies
from person to person.
At any age, as with many other drugs,
the brain and body become less sensitive
to marijuana after repeated uses,
meaning it takes more to
achieve the same effects.
Fortunately, unlike many other drugs,
there’s no risk of fatal /ˈfeɪtəl 致命的/ overdose /ˈəʊvəˌdəʊs 过量服用 沉溺/
from marijuana,
and even heavy use doesn’t
lead to debilitating /dɪˈbɪlɪˌteɪt 使虚弱，使衰弱/
or life-threatening withdrawal  /wɪðˈdrɔːəl 退出 撤走/
symptoms if use stops.
There are more subtle /ˈsʌtəl 稀薄的；微妙的/ forms of
marijuana withdrawal, though,
including sleep disturbances /dɪˈstɜːbəns 干扰；打乱/,
irritability /ˌɪrɪtəˈbɪlɪtɪ  易怒,过敏性,兴奋性/, and depressed mood,
which pass within a few weeks
of stopping use.
So is marijuana bad for your brain?
It depends who you are.
But while some risk factors are easy to
identify, others aren’t well understood—
which means there’s still some possibility
of experiencing negative effects,
even if you don’t have any of
the known risk factors.